Guide to the Elemer Nagy collection ARCH125
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
- Photographs, 1937-1971; undated; IV
  - Production Photograph Prints, 1937-1971; undated
    - Faust, 1971; undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Fidelio, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 19)
    - Fledermaus, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 20)
    - Fledermaus - Baltimore Civic, 1956 (Box Photographs 3, Folder 21)
    - Frantic Physician, 1942; 1944; 1970-1971 (Box Photographs 3, Folder 22, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Frantic Physician/Frogs/Yale, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 23)
    - Game of Carols, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 24)
    - Gianni Schicchi, 1947; undated (Box Shared Photograph Box 3, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Gooseherd and the Goblin, undated (Box Photographs 3, Folder 25)
    - Gypsy Baron - Central City, 1957 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 1)
    - Hansel and Gretel, 1948; undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 2, Box Shared Photograph Box 3, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Headless Horseman, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 3)
    - Hin and Zuruck, 1942 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 4)
    - History of a Soldier, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 5)
    - Love For Three Oranges, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 6)
    - Macbeth, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 7)
    - Madame Butterfly - Central City, 1950 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 8, Box Shared Photograph Box 3)
    - Magic Flute, 1964; undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 9, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
      Biographical / Historical
      Magic Flute was the first opera performed in Millard Auditorium.
    - Man in the Moon, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 10)
    - Marriage by Lantern Light, 1944 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 11)
    - Marriage of Figaro, 1952 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 12)
    - Marriage of the Devil, 1945 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 13)
    - Martha, 1946; 1954; undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 14-15, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Medea, 1970 Jan; undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 16-17)
    - Mephistofeles, 1968 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 18)
    - Merry Wives of Windsor, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 19)
    - Mighty Casey, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 20)
    - Miranda, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 21)
    - Old Maid and the Thief, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 22)
    - Pearl Fishers, 1964; undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 23, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Peer Gynt, 1965-1966; undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 24-25, Box Shared Photograph Box 3)
    - Polifem, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 26)
    - Prelude and Fugue, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 27)
    - Princess and the Vagabond, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 28, Box Shared Photograph Box 3, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Rigoletto Photos, 1956 (Box Photographs 4, Folder 29)
    - Romeo and Juliet - Hartt/Central City/Mobile, undated (Box Photographs 4, Folder 30, Box Shared Photograph Box 3)
    - Secret of Suzanne, undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 1)
    - Sister Angelica, 1970-1971; undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 2-3, Box Shared Photograph Box 3)
    - Sonambula, undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 4)
    - Suncatcher, undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 5)
    - Tales of Hoffman, 1958 (Box Photographs 5, Folder 6)
    - Telephone, undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 7)
    - Ten Maidens, undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 8)
    - Touchstone, 1955; undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 9, Box Set and Costume Design 45)
    - Traviata, 1960 (Box Photographs 5, Folder 10)
    - Turandot, 1967 (Box Photographs 5, Folder 11)
    - Vide Breve, undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 12)
    - White Wings, 1949; undated (Box Photographs 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Slides, 1958-1971; undated
    This subseries consists of 35mm slides of Elemer Nagy's productions, as well as his designs and images he used as inspiration for his work. Some slides may have also had instructional uses.
    - Ten Maidens, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 1)
    - Here and There, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 2)
    - Marriage by Lantern Light, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 3)
    - Old Maid and the Thief, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 4)
    - Frantic Physician, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 5)
    - Bastien and Bastienne, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 5)
    - Marriage of the Devil, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 7-8)
    - Secret of Suzanne, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 9)
    - Fact or Fiction, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 10)
    - Hansel and Gretel, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 11)
    - Sister Angelica, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 12-14)
    - Beauty and the Beast, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 15-19)
    - Amelia Goes to the Ball, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 20-22)
    - Martha, undated (Box Slides 1, Box 23-24, Box Slides 2, Box 1-2)
    - Barbara of Seville, undated (Box Slides 2, Box 3-8)
    - Gianni Schicchi, undated (Box Slides 2, Box 9-11)
    - Romeo and Juliet, undated (Box Slides 2, Box 12-15)
    - Princess and the Vagabond, undated (Box Slides 2, Box 16-21)
    - Telephone, undated (Box Slides 2, Box 22-23)
    - White Wings, undated (Box Slides 2, Box 24, Box Slides 3, Box 1-6)
    - Polifem, undated (Box Slides 3, Box 7-8)
    - Don Pasquale, undated (Box Slides 3, Box 9-14)
    - Merry Wives of Windsor, undated (Box Slides 3, Box 15-17)
    - Marriage of Figaro, undated (Box Slides 3, Box 18-21)
    - Beautiful Galatea, undated (Box Slides 3, Box 22-23)
    - Macbeth, undated (Box Slides 3, Box 24)
    - Devil and Daniel Webster, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 1-2)
    - Albert Herring, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 3-4)
    - Comedy of the Bridge, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 5)
    - Faust, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 6-7)
    - Touchstone, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 8-9)
    - Game of Cards, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 10)
    - Miranda and the Dark Young Man, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 11)
    - Armide, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 12-14)
    - Philemon and Baucis, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 15)
    - Amahl [?], undated (Box Slides 4, Box 16)
    - Tales of Hoffman, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 17-19)
    - Susannah, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 20-21)
    - Deidamia, undated (Box Slides 4, Box 22-24)
    - Preludes and Fugues, undated (Box Slides 5, Box 1-3)
    - Pearl Fishers, undated (Box Slides 5, Box 4-6)
    - Cosi [Fan Tutte?], undated (Box Slides 5, Box 7-9)
    - Falstaff, undated (Box Slides 5, Box 10-13)
    - Boris Godunov, undated (Box Slides 5, Box 14-17)
    - Barber of Seville, 1963 Oct (Box Slides 5, Box 18)
    - Fidelio?, 1963 Jul (Box Slides 5, Box 19)
    - Magic Flute, 1964 Feb (Box Slides 5, Box 20-22)
    - Crucible, 1964 Apr (Box Slides 5, Box 23-24)
    - Don Quixote, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 1-3)
    - Carmelites, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 4-8)
    - Peer Gynt, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 9-12)
    - Boheme, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 13-15)
    - Tales of Hoffman, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 16-18)
    - Ariadne, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 19-20)
    - Magic Flute, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 21-22)
    - Abduction, undated (Box Slides 6, Box 23-24, Box Slides 7, Box 1-2)
    - Sister Angelica, undated (Box Slides 7, Box 3)
    - Gianni Schicchi, undated (Box Slides 7, Box 4)
    - Hartt USO Tour, undated (Box Slides 7, Box 5-8)
    - Mefistofele, 1969 Feb (Box Slides 7, Box 9-13)
    - Young God, 1969 Apr (Box Slides 7, Box 14)
    - La Vide Breve, undated (Box Slides 7, Box 15-16)
    - Medea, 1970 Feb (Box Slides 7, Box 17-20)
    - Duenna, 1970 Apr (Box Slides 7, Box 21-24)
    - Pearl Fishers, 1971 Feb (Box Slides 8, Box 1-3)
    - Aspen?, 1960 Aug (Box Slides 8, Box 4-5)
    - Unidentified Opera, 1958 Aug (Box Slides 8, Box 6)
    - Tales of Hoffman, 1958 Feb (Box Slides 8, Box 7-8)
    - Unidentified, 1961 Nov (Box Slides 8, Box 9)
    - Unidentified, 1960 Dec (Box Slides 8, Box 10-11)
    - Unidentified, 1960 Aug (Box Slides 8, Box 12-13)
    - Unidentified, 1963 Dec (Box Slides 8, Box 14)
    - Unidentified, 1965 Sep (Box Slides 8, Box 15)
    - Aspen?, 1963 Oct (Box Slides 8, Box 16)
    - Unidentified, 1961 Dec (Box Slides 8, Box 17)
    - Unidentified, 1963 Jul (Box Slides 8, Box 18)
    - Barber of Seville (Aspen), 1966 Aug (Box Slides 8, Box 19-20)
    - Conway, 1967 June (Box Slides 8, Box 21-22)
    - Unidentified, 1968 Mar (Box Slides 8, Box 23)
    - Mefisto (Aspen), 1969 Nov (Box Slides 8, Box 24)
    - Frantic Physician (Yale), undated (Box Slides 9, Box 1-2)
    - Romeo and Juliet (Mobile), undated (Box Slides 9, Box 3)
    - People and Crew, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 4)
    - Concert Shell, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 5)
    - Concert Positions, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 6-7)
    - Gypsy Baron, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 8-11)
    - Romeo and Juliet, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 12-16)
    - Fledermaus, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 17-21)
    - Tosca Rigoletto, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 22)
    - Pasquale, undated (Box Slides 9, Box 23-24, Box Slides 10, Box 1-2)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box Slides 10, Box 3-14)
    - Madame Butterfly, undated (Box Slides 10, Box 15-20)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box Slides 10, Box 21-24, Box Slides 11, Box 1-8)
    - Model Workshop, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 9-11)
    - Cleveland Models, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 12)
    - Spherical Perspective, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 13-14)
    - Frantic Physician, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 15)
    - Hansel and Gretel, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 16)
    - Headless Horseman, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 17)
    - Bastien and Bastienne, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 18)
    - Marriage of the Devil, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 19)
    - Offenbach, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 20)
    - Apothecary, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 21)
    - Old Maid, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 22)
    - Sister Angelica, undated (Box Slides 11, Box 23-24)
    - Beauty and the Beast, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 1-2)
    - Secret of Suzanne, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 3)
    - Fact or Fiction, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 4)
    - Amelia, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 5-6)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 7-15)
    - Costumes History I, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 16-17)
    - Cosi Lecture, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 18-21)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box Slides 12, Box 22-24, Box Slides 13, Box 1-10)
    - Children Operas, undated (Box Slides 13, Box 11-23)
    - Acting Styles I, undated (Box Slides 14, Box 1-12)
    - Acting Styles II, undated (Box Slides 14, Box 13-21)
    - Acting Styles III, undated (Box Slides 14, Box 22-24, Box Slides 15, Box 1-9)
    - Acting Styles IV, undated (Box Slides 15, Box 10-20)
    - Acting Styles V, undated (Box Slides 15, Box 21-24, Box Slides 16, Box 1-5)
    - Acting Styles VI, undated (Box Slides 16, Box 6-14)
    - Acting Styles VII, undated (Box Slides 16, Box 15-19)
    - Multiprojection System backstage, 1958 Aug (Box Slides 16, Box 20)
  - Transparencies and Negatives, 1941-1971; undated
    This sub-series consists of negatives and transparencies of Elemer Nagy's productions, as well as his designs and images he used as inspiration for his work.
    This sub-series is arranged alphabetically.
    - Abduction from the Seraglio, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Albert Herring, 1962; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Amahl and The Night Visitors, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Amelia Goes to the Ball, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Apothecary / Frantic, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Ariadne auf Naxos, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Barber of Seville, 1963; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Bastien and Bastienne, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Beauty and the Beast, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Bluebeard Castle, Circa 1941 (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Boheme, 1966; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Boris, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Comedy on the Bridge, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Cosi Fan Tutte, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Crucible, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Cupid at the Boarding School, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Deidamia, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - The Devil and Daniel Webster, 1953 (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Dialogue ...Carmelites, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Dido and Aeneas, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Diemedia, 1959 Feb 20 (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Don Giovanni, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Don Pasquale, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Don Quixote, 1965 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Duenna, 1970 Apr; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Falstaff, 1961 Feb (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Faust, 1955 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Fidelio, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Fledermaus, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Forza del Destino, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Frantic Physician, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Frogs, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Game of Cards, 1956 May 1 (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Gianni Schicchi, Circa 1947; 1971 Apr; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Goblin and the Goosehead, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Gypsy Baron, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Hansel and Gretel, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Hartt School Operetta, Mrs. Jarvis Awards, 1952 May (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Haydn Il Mondo della Luna, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Headless Horseman, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Hin and Zuruck, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Little Red Riding Hood, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Lovely Galatea, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Macbeth, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Madame Butterfly, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Magic Flute, 1964 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Marriage by Lantern Light, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 1)
    - Marriage of Figaro, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Marriage of the Devil, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Martha, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Medea, 1970 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Medemia, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Mefistofele, 1969 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Merry Wives of Windsor, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Miranda and the Dark Young Man, 1956 May 1 (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Norma, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Old Maid and the Thief, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Pearl Fishers, 1971 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Peer Gynt, 1966 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Polifem, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Prelude and Fugue, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Princess and the Vagabond, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Rigoletto, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Romeo and Juliet, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Secret of Suzanne, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Sister Angelica, 1971 Apr; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Sonnambula, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Susannah, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Tales of Hoffman, 1968; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Telephone, 1948 May; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Ten Maidens and No Man, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Tosca, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Touchstone, 1955 May (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Vida Breve, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - White Wings, 1949 Feb; undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - Yale, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
    - The Young God, undated (Box Transparencies and Negatives 2)
      Includes several envelopes marked "Models," "Misc.," "Greek," "Olimpist," "Shop and Technical," and XVII Century."
- Subject Files, 1923-2002; undated; 1942-1971; VI
  This series contains various papers of Elemer Nagy by subject, most notable are the files pertaining to his correspondence, his multi-scenery projection system, and televised opera.
  The series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Aspen Music Festival, 1966-1969; undated (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 1)
  - Aspen Newspaper Clippings and Programs, 1961-1967 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 2)
  - Birthday, 1969 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 3)
  - Caricature, 1955 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 4)
  - Central City, 1949-1956; undated (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Central City Newspaper Articles, 1949-1954 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Columbia University, 1945 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Workshops, 1955; 1966 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 11)
  - Conway Mass, 1967 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 12)
  - Cooking and Hungarian Buffet Newspaper Clips, 1962; 1967 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 13)
  - Corning, Folton, Indiana, 1953-1954 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1970 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 15-22, Box Subject Files 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Cosi Fan Tutti, 1968-1970 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 4)
  - Design and Costume, Nagy Signature, undated (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 5)
  - Educational Lyric Theater Project (Ford Fd), 1953 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 6)
  - Elmer Nagy Tribute, 1971 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 7)
  - Empire State Music Festival, 1959 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 8)
  - European Tour, 1962 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 9)
  - Exams, Class List, 1968-1971 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 10)
  - Exhibits, 1950 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Data-Bio, 1947-1968 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 12)
  - Fort Worth Newspaper Articles, 1955; 1971 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 13)
  - Giannini, Vittorio, 1958 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 14)
  - Hartt Opera Guild, 1945-1946 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 15)
  - Inter-Collegiate Opera Group, 1955 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 1)
  - International Opera Production, 1966 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 2)
  - Julliard, 1967 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries, memorial, 1971-1972 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 4-6)
  - Opera Film, undated (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 7)
  - Opera for Children, 1954-1971 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 8)
  - Opera in English, 1953 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 9)
  - Opera Manual Central Opera Services, undated (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 10)
  - Opera News, 1966 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 11)
  - Opera News-Hansel and Gretel, 1946-1966 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 12)
  - Opera takes its staging ques from theatre, 1955 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969; undated (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 14)
  - Misc Newspaper Articles, 1947-1965 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 15)
  - Mobile, 1967; 1971 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 16)
  - Multiprojection System, undated (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 17)
  - Multiprojection System backstage, 1966-1971 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 18)
  - Multiprojection System-Manual, 1965 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 19)
  - Multiscenery Projection System, 2002; undated (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 20)
  - Musical America, 1943; 1956 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 21-22)
  - Music Clubs Magazine, 1957 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 23)
  - Nemeth Antal, 1933 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 24)
  - New England Opera Theatre, 1958 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 25)
  - New Plastic Effects, 1942 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 26)
  - News Releases, 1942-1971 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 27)
  - Notes on "La Pietra del Paragone", 1955 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 28)
  - NY Philharmonic, 1952 Nov 14 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 29)
  - Pollack's Theatre, undated (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 30)
  - Professional Activity, 1957-1966 (Box Subject Files 3, Folder 31)
  - Programs, 1943-1957 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 1)
    This file consists of correspondence pertaining to various programs in which Nagy participated in or directed. This file does not contain opera programs (documents distributed at opera performances), which are located in Series VII: Opera Programs, Printed Ephemera, and Their Designs.
  - Radio Opera Comes to the Stage Newspaper Article, 1946 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 2)
  - San Francisco, 1963 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 3)
  - Selected Opera Expert, undated (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 4)
  - Summer School of Music, 1952; 1954 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 5)
  - Tanglewood, 1957-1958 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 6)
  - Telecast, 1943-1944 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 7)
  - Television, 1944 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 8)
  - Television- General Electric, 1944 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 9)
  - Television Opera in Schenectady, 1945 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 10)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1958 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 11)
  - Theatre and Set Design, 1936-1965 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 12)
  - Theatre Notes, 1925-1947; undated (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Theatre- Perspective, Sets, Lantern Slides, undated (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 15)
  - Town Hall (NYC), 1952 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 16)
  - Ulysses Kay, Rosa Ponselle, Laurel Hurley, circa 1950's (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 17)
  - Utica, 1952 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 18)
  - Video Film, 1948 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 19)
  - Vitae, undated (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 20)
  - Writings, Interviews, 1943; 1955; undated (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 21)
  - Writings by Others, 1923; 1929; undated (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 22, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 7, Folder 1)
  - Writings by Others, undated (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 23)
  - Zador, Eugene, 1955 (Box Subject Files 4, Folder 24)
- Publicity and Scrapbooks, 1932-2002; 1932-1971; undated; V
  This series contains newspaper clippings, reviews, and scrapbooks regarding the work of Elemer Nagy primarily from 1932-1971. A library newsletter from 2002 about his collection in the archives was added to the collection later.
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  - Scrapbooks, 1932-1937 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 1)
  - Model Stage, 1938 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale, 1939 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 3)
  - The Apothecary, 1940 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 4)
  - Yale, 1940 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 5)
  - Albany, 1940 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 6)
  - Yale University Theatre Scrapbook, 1940-1941, undated (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 7, Folder 2)
  - Cleveland, 1941 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 7-8)
  - The Frantic Physician, 1941 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 9)
  - The Frogs of Aristophanes, 1941 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 10)
  - Theatre Model Reconstructions, 1941 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 11)
  - Yale Art Gallery, 1942 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 12)
  - Avery, 1942 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 13)
  - Cleveland, 1942 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 14)
  - Hansel and Gretel, 1942 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 15)
  - General Publicity, May 1942 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 16)
  - Hartt Opera, history, 1942 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 17)